<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on ecmccfg</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on ecmccfg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ecmc server</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/host/</guid><description>Topics latency issues EtherCAT rate (EC_RATE) latency issues High latency, more than 10% of the ethercat cycle time, can in worse case result, in lost ethercat frames, which of course is not an ideal situation. High latency of the ecmc_rt thread can be related to:
The generic device driver is used High load on system &amp;hellip; generic device driver is used Check which driver is in use by running (on the ecmc server):</description></item><item><title>EL5042</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</guid><description>Topics error/warning Diagnostics Offset LSB Bit [Bit] (0x80p8:17) SSI error/warning Could be caused by:
Wrong settings (bit counts, ..), see further below on this page (and also motion/best practice). Bad electrical connection Wrong power supply Defect encoder or EL5042 Long cabling lengths Always start troubleshooting by checking the error, warning and ready bits and reading the EL5042 manual. Next step is to read the diagnostic SDO bits of the EL5042, see below under heading &amp;ldquo;Diagnostics&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>EL70x1</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</guid><description>Topics error/warning Tuning error/warning If the drive is in error or warning state, further information about the reason for the warning/error can be read from the drive terminal by using the ethercat command. See command line interface for more info.
In order to use the ethercat command, you must first login to the server where the ecmc IOC is running.
The diagnostic data can be read from register Index A010 STM Diag data Ch.</description></item><item><title>EL9xxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</guid><description>Topics over current protection passive terminals over current protection In the standard setup at PSI over current protection modules are used to feed 24V to both the EtherCAT communication bus (E-bus) and the power bus of the EtherCAT slaves. If the over current protection is not enabled then the EtherCAT slaves will not receive power.
First time, (and only first time), a system is in use, the over-current modules needs to be enabled in order to allow current to flow.</description></item></channel></rss>