<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on ecmccfg</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on ecmccfg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ELxxxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/elxxxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/elxxxx/</guid><description>Power bus - 5V or 24V terminals 24V is the most common signal level for the terminals, however, some also support other voltage levels, for instance 5V, or 12V or&amp;hellip;. In that case, normally the terminal needs to be powered with the same voltage. For 5V terminals, normally a EL9505 is added before the 5v terminal in the ethercat chain supplying the power bus with 5V.
Example of slaves needing 5V power supply:</description></item><item><title>EL1xxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el1xxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el1xxx/</guid><description>EL1252, EL1252-0050 EL1252-xxxx is a 2 ch digital input terminal with timestamps (low to high, high to low):
EL1252: 24V signals EL1252-0050: 5V signals Both terminals have the product id and process data and can therefore be configured as EL1252:
# One channel: ${SCRIPTEXEC} ${ecmccfg_DIR}addSlave.cmd, &amp;quot;SLAVE_ID=16, HW_DESC=EL1252&amp;quot; These terminals are very powerful since they can latch the time of the positive edge and/or negative edge of the input signal (independent of the ethercat bus rate).</description></item><item><title>EL5042</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</guid><description>Topics error/warning Diagnostics Offset LSB Bit [Bit] (0x80p8:17) SSI 9V supply error/warning/not ready Could be caused by:
Wrong settings (bit counts, ..), see further below on this page (and also motion/best practice). Bad electrical connection Wrong power supply Defect encoder or EL5042 Long cabling lengths Wrong communication frequency Always start troubleshooting by checking the error, warning and ready bits and reading the EL5042 manual. Next step is to read the diagnostic SDO bits of the EL5042, see below under heading &amp;ldquo;Diagnostics&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>EL51xx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el51xx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el51xx/</guid><description>Overview The EL51xx series covers incremental encoder interfaces:
EL5101: 1 ch, diff rs422, ttl, 1MHz EL5101-0010: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz EL5101-0011: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz, oversampling 100kHz EL5112: 2 ch ABC or 1 ch AB, rs422, 5MHz, PSI standard EL5131: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz, 2 digital outputs for cam/trigger General Normally, the incremental encoder interfaces do not require any SDO configuration. Therefore, the ecmccomp/applyComponent.cmd, which many times are needed after the ecmccfg/addSlave.</description></item><item><title>EL7062</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el7062/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el7062/</guid><description>Topics error/warning openloop counter jump tuning home on index pulse of incremental encoder error/warning If the drive is in error/warning state and not possible to enable, see drive refuse to enable.
The most common reason for this error is:
motor is not connected (PSI specific): motor cable in wrong connector (at PSI motor and limits have the same 5pin M12 connector) drive has no motor voltage (PSI specific): EL9227-5500 feeding the I/O bus is not initiated (at first power on the switches on the terminal needs to be engaged) Openloop counter jump The EL7062 has a firmware bug if configured to run in open loop CSV.</description></item><item><title>EL70x1</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</guid><description>Topics error/warning tuning Speed range error/warning If the drive is in error/warning state and not possible to enable, see drive refuse to enable.
The most common reason for this error is:
motor is not connected (PSI specific): motor cable in wrong connector (at PSI motor and limits have the same 5pin M12 connector) drive has no motor voltage (PSI specific): EL9227-5500 feeding the I/O bus is not initiated (at first power on the switches on the terminal needs to be engaged) Further information about the error/warning can be read from from the drive&amp;rsquo;s diagnostic register, Index A010 STM Diag data Ch.</description></item><item><title>EL72xx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el72xx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el72xx/</guid><description>Topics error/warning error/warning If the drive is in error/warning state and not possible to enable:
Missing power supply STO tripped Defect cable Wrong/messey cabling between connector and actual terminal. Tuning ** Always be prepared to &amp;ldquo;KILL&amp;rdquo; or estop the axes while performing tuning**
Make sure scaling factors are correct. Test by setting ecmc position controller parameters to 0 and perform a move. This move will basically be a openloop positioning.</description></item><item><title>EL9xxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</guid><description>Topics over current protection passive terminals over current protection In the standard setup at PSI over current protection modules are used to feed 24V to both the EtherCAT communication bus (E-bus) and the power bus of the EtherCAT slaves. If the over current protection is not enabled then the EtherCAT slaves will not receive power.
First time, (and only first time), a system is in use, the over-current modules needs to be enabled in order to allow current to flow.</description></item><item><title>Hardware issues</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/hardware_issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/hardware_issues/</guid><description>Hardware List of hardware issues at PSI:
Date Type Description 03.06.25 Cable OCT cable failure. Motor enable lost frequently, error bit on drives set.</description></item></channel></rss>