<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on ecmccfg</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on ecmccfg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ELxxxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/elxxxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/elxxxx/</guid><description>5V and 24V terminals 24V is the most common signal level for the terminals, however, a few terminals also support other voltage levels, for instance 5V. In that case, normally the terminal needs to be powered with the same voltage. For 5V terminals, normally this is handled by adding a EL9505 before the 5v terminal in the ethercat chain. The EL9505 will supply the power bus with 5V instead of the normal 24V .</description></item><item><title>EL1xxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el1xxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el1xxx/</guid><description>EL1252, EL1252-0050 EL1252-xxxx is a 2 ch digital input terminal with timestamps (low to high, high to low):
EL1252: 24V signals EL1252-0050: 5V signals Both terminals have the product id and process data and can therefore be configured as EL1252:
# One channel: ${SCRIPTEXEC} ${ecmccfg_DIR}addSlave.cmd, &amp;quot;SLAVE_ID=16, HW_DESC=EL1252&amp;quot; These terminals are very powerful since they can latch the time of the positive edge and/or negative edge of the input signal (independent of the ethercat bus rate).</description></item><item><title>EL5042</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el5042/</guid><description>Topics error/warning Diagnostics Offset LSB Bit [Bit] (0x80p8:17) SSI error/warning Could be caused by:
Wrong settings (bit counts, ..), see further below on this page (and also motion/best practice). Bad electrical connection Wrong power supply Defect encoder or EL5042 Long cabling lengths Always start troubleshooting by checking the error, warning and ready bits and reading the EL5042 manual. Next step is to read the diagnostic SDO bits of the EL5042, see below under heading &amp;ldquo;Diagnostics&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>EL51xx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el51xx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el51xx/</guid><description>Overview The EL51xx series covers incremental encoder interfaces:
EL5101: 1 ch, diff rs422, ttl, 1MHz EL5101-0010: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz EL5101-0011: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz, oversampling 100kHz EL5112: 2 ch ABC or 1ch AB, rs422, 5MHz, PSI standard EL5131: 1 ch, diff rs422, 5MHz, 2 digital outputs for cam/trigger General Normally, the incremental encoder interfaces do not require any SDO configuration. Therefore, the ecmccomp/applyComponent.cmd, which many times are needed after the ecmccfg/addSlave.</description></item><item><title>EL9xxx</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el9xxx/</guid><description>Topics over current protection passive terminals over current protection In the standard setup at PSI over current protection modules are used to feed 24V to both the EtherCAT communication bus (E-bus) and the power bus of the EtherCAT slaves. If the over current protection is not enabled then the EtherCAT slaves will not receive power.
First time, (and only first time), a system is in use, the over-current modules needs to be enabled in order to allow current to flow.</description></item><item><title>EL70x1</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/knowledgebase/hardware/el70x1/</guid><description>Topics error/warning Tuning error/warning If the El70x1 is in error or warning state, further information about the reason for the error/warning can be read from the drives diagnostic register by using the ethercat command. See command line interface.
In order to use the ethercat command, you must first login to the server where the ecmc IOC is running.
The diagnostic data can be read from register Index A010 STM Diag data Ch.</description></item></channel></rss>