<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>troubleshooting on ecmccfg</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/</link><description>Recent content in troubleshooting on ecmccfg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>general</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/general/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/general/</guid><description>culprit From experience, very few issues are related to the EtherCAT hardware itself. Mostly the cabling or the actual motor/encoder hardware is to blame.
Even more likely is human error, such as:
wrong scaling of the axis writing to the wrong hardware (forgot to select the right slave in the axis config) &amp;hellip; check the status Before anything is restarted or power cycled, check the status of the system.</description></item><item><title>ethercat command line interface</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/ethercatcli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/ethercatcli/</guid><description>ethercat CLI The IgH EtherCAT master provides a command line interface (CLI) which is a very powerful tool. The most common commands will be explained here.
ethercat master This will show the state of all masters on the respective host.
The command will show the state of all masters. To limit the command to a single master, make use of the -m parameter.
The -m parameter is available to all ethercat commands, and is even require by some in case of multiple masters.</description></item><item><title>motion</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/motion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/motion/</guid><description>Topics both_limits error position lag error, (following error), tuning latency issues drive refuse to enable both_limits error The &amp;ldquo;BOTH_LIMITS&amp;rdquo; error can be related to that limits switches are not powered with 24V. As standard at PSI, limts are feed from 24V outputs, normally an EL2819 terminal. Basically the ouptputs needs then to be set to 1 in order to power the switches. Check the schematics in order to find out which output that powers the switches for a certain axis and then use one the following approaches to set it to 1:</description></item><item><title>hardware</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/tuning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/tuning/</guid><description>EL70x1 Tuning For EL70x1 stepper drives the following parameters can be tuned:
8011:07 Ka factor 8011:08 Kd factor 8011:01 Kp factor 8011:02 Ki factor 8011:07 Ka and 8011:08 Kd factor: 8011:07 Ka factor / 8011:08 Kd factor are “current boosts” during acceleration/deceleration. Default they are set to 100% which is way too high for most applications. Start by setting these parameters to 0.
8011:01 Kp and 8011:02 Ki factor: This is the current loop settings and this is also what affect the performance.</description></item><item><title>hardware</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/hardware/</guid><description>Topics [over current protection](#over current protection) [el7041 error/warning](#el7041 error/warning) [latency issues](#latency issues) over current protection In the standard setup at PSI over current protection modules are used to feed 24V to both the ethercat communication bus (E-bus) and the power bus of the ethercat slaves. If the over current protection is not enabled then the ethercat slaves will not receive power.
First time, (and only first time), a system is in use, the overcurrent modules needs to be enabled in order to allow current to flow.</description></item><item><title>manual motion</title><link>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://paulscherrerinstitute.github.io/ecmccfg/manual/troubleshooting/manual/</guid><description>force manual motion This procedure is for experts only. You run the risk of destroying expansive devices! Limit switches are not obeyed! YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED!
In case the hardware is fine, the cables are checked, human error is mostly excluded, or the system used to work but doesn&amp;rsquo;t work any longer, directly writing to the drive is possible.
For this however, the IOC needs to be reconfigured to not link the hardware to an axis!</description></item></channel></rss>